Until the very last second...
none of us are giving up!
THIS ONE IS MINE!
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
Nice dive, bro!
Defend the basket!
Everybody go back!
Chiaki!
He kept it in!
Kite is totally open.
We can score 2 points for sure.
Do I pass?
No.
Our whole team is already running on empty!
If this goes into overtime,
then we'll lose for sure!
The only way to win this...
...is by going all in... from here!
I couldn't reach it!
Son of a bitch!
GO IN!
He missed!
That damn bonehead!
It's coming down! Run for it!
It's not over yet! Don't give up!
If we can get it, then...
Time's up! The game is over!
Back to the mirror, my dream getting
farther with every step I take
I want to come face-to-face with you
Saying to the incapable version
of myself, "never mind"
Ahiru no Sora
A dream slowly dismantled
on the assembly line
(Suitable? Unsuitable?
Pretty much impossible?)
True feelings gone missing without a whisper
(Not even capable of a sigh)
None of it will end by
placing the blame on others
Right now, in the face of a steep slope
My heart cries out for me to "overcome it"
Finding excuses not to try is
something that anybody can do
Pushing myself to run beyond, I
went to meet a me I've never known
There's graffiti etched on the
wall that says "never mind"
Now, I bounce into tomorrow
Time's up! The game is over!
Kuzuryu
Kitasumiyoshi
With the score at 76 to 74,
Tears
the winner is Kitasumiyoshi High School!
We won!
Thanks for the game!
It's always like this...
I just end up hurting the person I love.
But no matter what...
my feelings for Nao will never change!
Looks like I won. It's over, Momoharu.
Let's be clear, you didn't beat me.
But Kuzu High did lose
and it's because I held the team back.
I'll concede that much.
Thank you for the game!
Sure.
See ya, dude.
Thanks for the game.
Thanks...
You made quite a big mistake
with that last three-pointer, eh?
Yes... I think so, too.
It was our last chance to make a comeback,
so I got scared of being blocked from behind.
It kept me from following
through on the shot.
It's all because I'm still so shor-
No, that's not what I'm talking about.
Huh?
I certainly agree that it
was a poorly made shot,
but the biggest mistake you
made was even before that.
Even before that?
You hesitated whether to pass
it or shoot it, didn't you?
While it's true that Taro was right on your heels,
you had a whole 4 seconds.
That's plenty of time to throw in a fake
and then take a breath for a moment.
Or if you had kept your cool,
you might have thought about drawing a foul.
Actually, that would have been the best option
to assure you made a comeback.
There's no doubt, the biggest mistake you made
in that last play...
...was not looking at the basket
the instant you got your hands on the ball.
After #7 saved the ball,
you should have noticed #11 ahead of you
and felt more at ease about everything.
Because a tie was possible,
even in the worst-case.
If this had happened in the first-half,
you would have gone straight for the shot.
Am I wrong?
Changing positions in the last quarter
ended up costing you, huh?
Thank you very much.
Oh, sure. Let's play again sometime soon.
I would really enjoy it.
In any case... out of 9 attempts
at three-pointers, he sank 7 of them.
Even with numbers like that,
it's not exactly surprising
that he missed the very last one.
Only 150 centimeters tall, eh?
If you ask me, players like him
are going to be...
indispensable to the future of basketball.
BOYS'
BASKETBALL
TEAM
It was a close game, guys.
We nearly had it.
But damn, I'm exhausted.
Whoa, even my jersey is
totally soaked with sweat.
I can't get my body to move an inch...
Well, my dudes, I'm just glad nobody died
after all the training.
This was just a damn practice match...
and we still got our asses whooped!
This is the worst.
What's with him?
Kite...
Dammit!
Yo, seriously? Not you too, Momoharu.
Come on, guys. Isn't Kitasumi supposed to be
just as strong as Maru High?
We did pretty damn well to come so far
against Kitasumi if you consider that, right?
I mean, we only lost by 2 points!
We've only been a team for about a month,
which means we're making good prog-
You just don't get it.
Huh?
We lost by 2 points against a team
that wasn't even trying.
What do you mean by that?
They weren't using their best players.
Didn't you notice?
Kitasumi didn't have a #4 on the court,
even though that should be their captain.
N-now that you mention it...
And I'm betting that #10 and #14
are normally substitutes.
It's safe to assume they have
at least 3 other players who are even better.
On top of that, Kitasumi never made
any substitutions in this game.
They also only used one of their timeouts
at the very beginning.
Meanwhile, we had to use all 5 of ours.
That's crazy...
So, does this mean we suck...?
That's the reality of it,
just look at the facts.
We lost...
The difference between you and me is...
the fact I have wings and you don't.
The biggest mistake you
made in that last play...
...was not looking at the basket
the instant you got your hands on the ball.
We lost!
Goddammit!
Now's not the time... I
should just leave him be.
Thank you for coming today.
Hey! Wait a sec! Please!
Just let go of me, you guys!
Nao! NAO!
Sorry about this...
I'll call you!
Such a strange feeling.
I was only just a spectator...
but it's still frustrating.
This is all my fault.
Everyone... placed their
faith in me and my strategy.
Hey, Nao. Don't you have a
plan or something to help?
It was only for a second...
but I gave up on us winning.
And that's not the worst part,
even my game plan turned out flawed...
Next time. You can win then.
Right...
I'm the worst!
I couldn't even stay on my feet for the whole match!
Yet I spouted all that cocky shit about winning!
Natsume...
So fucking pathetic!
Nanao. Gather all of the boys together.
Huh?
Let's go out and have BBQ for dinner.
But that was only if we won the match...
I'll give you a reward in
advance... for your next victory.
So, to sum it up, we've got a school-wide
sports tournament coming up soon.
SELECTING PLAYERS FOR THE
SCHOOL-WIDE SPORTS TOURNEY
We're going to decide who will be representing
this class in each game.
My muscles are so sore, I can hardly move...
If you'd like to participate,
then please raise your hand.
We'll start with the boys.
Who wants to play softball?
I don't feel like doing anything today...
I just wanna go home...
Okay. Then the next sport is... basketball.
Um, anybody?
Freshman are allowed to play in any
sport, even if they're on the school team.
So please...
Count me out.
Madoka
So, the team doesn't have any practice today?
Then let's walk home together (^0^)
Do we have anybody that's
on the basketball team?
No way, nobody wanted to join those guys.
No kidding. They're scary as shit.
Madoka
So, the team doesn't have any practice today?
Then let's walk home together (^0^)
Oh, but wait, I thought
that Kurumatani was...
Huh?
I'm totally in! Let's play ball!
Come on, everybody! It'll be a ton of fun!
Dude, calm down!
Wait, Kurumatani!
Oh, hey, Nanao!
What's got you in such a rush?
Don't tell me that you're headed
to the gym for practice.
I thought I was clear, everybody is ordered
to recuperate today!
Uh, well...
Hold it right there!
Oh crap!
I am NOT letting you skip out
on cleaning duty ever again!
Sorry! But I've got something
super important to do today!
Come back here!
Something super important...?
I'm sorry, but uh...
...I don't think I'll be
headed home anytime soon.
Oh yeah?
No problem, I'll just wait
for you in my classroom.
Jeez. This is what he gets for
skipping out all the time.
Will you... make sure that Sora gets this?
I had no idea people's arms
could even get that thin...
It scared me to see that.
I wonder how serious her illness is?
Is it really okay if I hide the fact
this is a gift from his mother?
Crap! It's been 30 minutes already!
Madoka might have gone home by now!
I'm gonna have to find a new way
to escape from our class rep...
I'd like to talk to you
for a sec. Do you mind?
Look, I was just wondering
if you'd go out with me sometime...
Ever since we met last year...
I've been totally into you.
Oh... um, well...
Actually... I have feelings for someone else.
I'm sorry.
Damn... that must've hit hard.
You sneak.
Did you hear all that?
Hear what? I have no idea what you mean.
I guess Madoka must get a lot
of attention like that...
But wait, she said she
had feelings for someone.
Who is that?
Maybe I should ask...
Hey.
Tell me, Sora, is there anybody
you have the hots for?
Huh? WHAT?!
No! Um, well, there's... there's
nobody in particular who I-
Okay, then how about you
tell me who your type is.
What kind of people have
you fallen for in the past?
Wh-who I fell for in the past?
Um, well... first, my teacher from kindergarten,
then in 3rd grade, Micchan who was a year above me,
then in middle school, a senpai
who was two grades above me, and...
So basically, he likes them older.
But...
All of them were taller
than I was at the time...
...so I think that my feelings
were pretty far from actual love.
This is especially true out on the court,
but it's kinda painful for me
to only be seen from above.
All right, Sora. Close your eyes for me.
Huh?
Just do it.
Uh, okay!
For real?! She's just going for it?!
Keep those eyes shut real tight, all right?
Okay! Look over this way.
Is this better?
U-uh, no, well...
A gap in height isn't such a big deal,
in love or basketball.
Trust me.
Madoka...
The reason I asked you to come with me today is because
I have something to give you.
Huh?! For me?! Are you serious?!
Put your arm out.
S-sure!
Because... she's the only one who has ever
supported my passion for basketball.
He's keeping it all a big secret from her.
Is my son... having a good
time playing basketball?
Okay!
Isn't this... the wristband
that I always see you wearing in the gym?
Consider it a good luck charm
to help you win your next game! Okay?
You'll be playing for keeps soon.
So I don't want you to lose, no matter what!
Y-y-y-y-y-you can count on me!
I'll DEFINITELY win the next one for sure!
Great. I look forward to it.
All right!
Bring it on!
I'm so sorry, Mrs. Yuka.
I can't be the one who gives it to him.
If he ends up getting it from me, then...
...the true meaning behind
it will be lost for sure.
Get ready for the
School-wide Sports Tourney
Much excite!
No graffiti!!
Get hype!
Today!!!
Do it!
Defeat Class 2!!!!
Yeah!
Cute!
Two outs!
You survived! Way to hold it together, man!
Hey, you guys! I think we're
gonna need a new catcher!
I smell another victory
on the horizon this year.
My popularity with the girls
is going to skyrocket!
Is that all you've guys got?
My class is bunch of spineless wimps.
I'll show you how to deal
with this fool's weak-ass pitches.
Prepare yourself, you're facing a man
who is destined for the major leagues!
But you're on the basketball team...
Well, Nabe. You're the first batter I've seen
with any balls today.
If you manage to hit a homerun off of me,
then I'll give you a 1,000 funbucks.
Don't be a cheapskate.
Make it 5,000 funbucks.
You're a greedy little punk.
Fine then.
The hell are "funbucks"?
You know, Nabe, we've been friends
since back in Elementary.
It's been a long road for us.
Yeah, it sure has.
What now? This is turning into
some kind of soap opera...
People would often confuse us as being twins just because
we both grew out manly facial hair.
Yeah, they sure did.
Did they really though?
But now!
I've cast aside all the sentiment
that I had for our past!
Let's do this!
Bring it!
What the?! Why'd the
weather suddenly change?!
F-flames?!
He hit it! He actual hit it!
You're the first man to
ever hit one of my pitches.
I can't send Chiaki's pitches flying
with a flimsy piece of shit like this!
Bring me a metal bat right now!
B-but you'll die, Nabeshima...
Shut it!
This right here is a deathmatch
with the pride of two men at stake!
The damn ball could gouge my heart out
and I still wouldn't go down!
And honestly, I kind of
want those 5,000 funbucks!
No seriously, what are "funbucks"?
There's no man on Earth capable
of hitting my pitches!
You're wrong, there is one man!
And his name is Ryuhei Nabeshima!
Huh...?
He hit it right out of the
park! It's a home run!
Nice, Nabe!
Class 2-1 is the winner this year!
Thanks, dudes! Thanks for cheering me on!
Touch.
Huh?
Dude, that's a different ball
that was just lying around.
Nope, I caught yours when no one was looking.
That's a load of bull!
There's no way you caught that ball!
You all saw it go flying, right?!
It went out of the park for sure!
We didn't see nothing...
Three outs! Change!
What the hell?! Why are you asswipes
pretending you didn't see anything?!
Do your best, Yoshihara!
Keep it up!
Move it, runt! Or else I'll send you flying!
Ugh, what a huge jerk...
C'mon, pissant!
Pass the ball here!
Wow! He's amazing!
So cool!
That punkass freshman!
Let's knock him down a peg!
Hold it, you little shit!
Get ready for a knuckle sandwich!
Eat shit, fool.
Game over!
With the score at 12 to 4,
class 1-3 is the winner!
Holy cow! The freshmen
totally trashed the seniors!
All the new students are
pretty damn good at sports!
Oh my gosh, isn't Natsume just the coolest?!
Although he's still a little scary.
He's totally awesome! Especially that move,
the double-whatever they call it!
I've seen it in a sports manga before!
Do you think he has a girlfriend yet?
Oh jeez, I don't believe it...
I'm totally going to ask for his number later!
...they're all fawning over him...
Our class is definitely going to win in basketball.
Nobody stands a chance against Natsume.
Totally! It's in the bag!
I'm not so sure it will be as simple as that.
Since there's an amazing player
in the class next to ours.
An amazing player?
Just look. Over on that court.
Hey Kida, move further inside!
Oh, uhhh... yeah, Kurumatani right?
The short kid everybody was talking about.
Is he the amazing player you mean?
Just watch. He'll definitely surprise you.
What a move!
Nice pass, Kurumatani!
Huh? A pass? But why?
So close!
Umm... sorry, Nao. I really don't get
what's so amazing about him.
Uh, well, that's okay.
Maybe he's... focused solely
on being point guard?
At 8 points to 6, the winner is class 1-4!
We did it!
Wow! The freshmen managed
to survive to the next game!
That means the next match is
between class 1-3 and 1-4.
The winner of that is probably
going to go all the way.
Oh man, Kudo! That last
shot you made was perfect!
Right? I'm totally awesome!
Hey, send me some passes too!
Sure, leave it to me!
We wouldn't have lost if you'd made solid passes
like that to me during OUR game.
Huh?
I have no plans to lose again,
no matter what team I have to go up against from now on.
That also includes you, shrimp.
Even if things aren't going well on my own
There's a simple way to turn it all around
A light falls down on an
exit previously unseen
That's where the path to tomorrow lies
I was never really alone to begin with
You were in the scenery reflected in my eyes
I can go anywhere so long as you stay there
There are no such things as limits
Just having you by my side makes me stronger
We'll pick ourselves up as
often as needed and keep moving
Oh oh oh, oh oh oh, oh oh oh,
Until the very last second
Don't give up and keep fighting
A shining light is undoubtedly
waiting for us down this path
Ahiru no Sora
Next Time: The Last Piece
Next time: "The Last Piece."